def get_flashcards_content():
    flashcards_by_year = {
    
        #Year 1 Microeconomics Flashcards
        'Microeconomics_1': [
            {
                'front': "What is Economic development?",
                'back': "Improvements in living standards"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Ceteris paribus?",
                'back': "All other things remaining the same"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Positive statements?",
                'back': "Statements which are objective and can be tested to be proven or disproven"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Normative statements?",
                'back': "Statements which are subjective and based on opinion, cannot be proven or disproven"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Scarcity?",
                'back': "The shortage of resources in relation to the quantity of human wants"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is the Economic problem?",
                'back': "The problem of scarcity; wants are unlimited by resources are finite so choices have to be made"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Opportunity cost?",
                'back': "The value of the next best alternative forgone"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Efficiency?",
                'back': "When resources are allocated optimally, so every consumer benefits and waste is minimised"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Labour?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; human capital"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Capital?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; goods which can be used in the production process"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Enterprise?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; the willingness and ability to take risks and combine the three other factors of production"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Land?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; natural resources such as oil, coal, wheat, physical space"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Ad valorem tax?",
                'back': "An indirect tax imposed on a good where the value of the tax is dependent on the value of the good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Demand?",
                'back': "The quantity of a good/service that consumers are able and willing to buy at a given price at a given moment in time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Supply?",
                'back': "The ability and willingness to provide a particular good/service at a given price at a given moment in time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Price mechanism?",
                'back': "The system of resource allocation based on the free market movement of prices, determined by the demand and supply curves"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Equilibrium price/quantity?",
                'back': "Where demand equals supply so there are no more market forces bringing about change to price or quantity sold"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Command economy?",
                'back': "All factors of production are allocated by the state, so they decide what, how and for whom to produce goods"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Free market?",
                'back': "An economy where the market mechanism allocates resources so consumers and producers make decision about what is produced, how to produce it and for whom"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Mixed economy?",
                'back': "Both the free market mechanism and the government allocate resources"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Ceteris paribus?",
                'back': "All other things remaining the same"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Scarcity?",
                'back': "The shortage of resources in relation to the quantity of human wants"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is the Economic problem?",
                'back': "The problem of scarcity; wants are unlimited by resources are finite so choices have to be made"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Opportunity cost?",
                'back': "The value of the next best alternative forgone"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Efficiency?",
                'back': "When resources are allocated optimally, so every consumer benefits and waste is minimised"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Capital?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; goods which can be used in the production process"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Capital goods?",
                'back': "Goods produced in order to aid production of consumer goods in the future"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Enterprise?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; the willingness and ability to take risks and combine the three other factors of production"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Labour?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; human capital"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Land?",
                'back': "One of the four factors of production; natural resources such as oil, coal, wheat, physical space"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Asymmetric information?",
                'back': "Where one party has more information than the other, leading to market failure"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Market failure?",
                'back': "When the free market fails to allocate resources to the best interest of society, so there is an inefficient allocation of scarce resources"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Externalities?",
                'back': "The cost of benefit a third party receives from an economic transaction outside of the market mechanism"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are External costs/benefits?",
                'back': "The cost/benefit to a third party not involved in the economic activity; the difference between social cost/benefit and private cost/benefit"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Government failure?",
                'back': "When government intervention leads to a net welfare loss in society"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Price elasticity of demand?",
                'back': "The responsiveness of demand to a change in price"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Price elasticity of supply?",
                'back': "The responsive of supply to a change in price"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Income elasticity of demand (YED)?",
                'back': "The responsiveness of demand to a change in income"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Cross elasticity of demand (XED)?",
                'back': "The responsiveness of demand for one good to a change in the price of another good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Complementary goods?",
                'back': "Negative XED; if good B becomes more expensive, demand for good A falls"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Substitutes?",
                'back': "Positive XED; if good B becomes more expensive, demand for good A rises"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Consumer goods?",
                'back': "Goods bought and demanded by households and individuals"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Consumer surplus?",
                'back': "The difference between the price the consumer is willing to pay and the price they actually pay"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Producer surplus?",
                'back': "The difference between the price the producer is willing to charge and the price they actually charge"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Utility?",
                'back': "The satisfaction derived from consuming a good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Diminishing marginal utility?",
                'back': "The extra benefit gained from consumption of a good generally declines as extra units are consumed; explains why the demand curve is downward sloping"
            }
        ],
        #Year 1 Macroeconomics Flashcards
        'Macroeconomics_1': [
            {
                'front': "What is Economic growth?",
                'back': "An increase in the long term productive potential of the economy; an increase in the amount of goods and services which are produced, measured by an increase in real GDP"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Actual growth?",
                'back': "Economic growth measured by changes in real GDP"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Potential growth?",
                'back': "A change in the productive potential of the economy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Long run trend rate of growth?",
                'back': "The average sustainable rate of economic growth over a period of time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Output gap?",
                'back': "The difference between the long term trend rate of growth and actual growth"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Positive output gap?",
                'back': "When GDP is higher than predicted; the economy is producing above full output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Negative output gap?",
                'back': "When GDP is lower than predicted; the economy is producing below full output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Gross Domestic Product (GDP)?",
                'back': "The value of goods and services produced in a country over a given period of time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Real GDP?",
                'back': "GDP which strips out the effect of inflation"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Nominal GDP?",
                'back': "GDP which does not take inflation into account; GDP at current prices"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is GDP per capita?",
                'back': "Total GDP divided by the population"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Gross National Income (GNI)?",
                'back': "The value of goods and services produced by a country over a period of time plus net overseas interest payments and dividends"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Gross National Product (GNP)?",
                'back': "The value of goods and services produced by citizens of a country, whether they live in the country or not"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is National income?",
                'back': "The value of money paid by firms to households in return for land, labour, capital and enterprise"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is National expenditure?",
                'back': "The value of spending by households on goods and services"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is National output?",
                'back': "The value of the flow of goods and services from firms to households"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Inflation?",
                'back': "The general rise in prices of goods and services that erodes the purchasing power of money"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Consumer Price Index?",
                'back': "Official measure used to calculate the rate of inflation, using a weighted basket of goods"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Retail Price Index (RPI)?",
                'back': "An old measure of inflation which has lost its national statistic status"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Base year?",
                'back': "A year chosen as a good comparison in a series of data when building an index; it is automatically given an index figure of 100"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Cost push inflation?",
                'back': "Inflation caused by a decrease in AS"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Demand pull inflation?",
                'back': "Inflation caused by an increase in AD"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Deflation?",
                'back': "A persistent fall in prices of goods and services"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Disinflation?",
                'back': "A reduction in the rate of inflation"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is the definition of Employed?",
                'back': "Someone who does more than 1 hour of paid work a week or is temporarily away from work, on a government supported training scheme or does a minimum of 15 hours unpaid work for their family business (ILO definition)"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is the definition of Unemployed?",
                'back': "Those who are without work, able to start work in the next 2 weeks and have actively sought work for the last 4 weeks (ILO definition)"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Cyclical unemployment?",
                'back': "Unemployment caused by a lack of AD"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Frictional unemployment?",
                'back': "Unemployment caused when people move between jobs and enter the job market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Structural unemployment?",
                'back': "Unemployment caused by the long term decline of an industry"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Seasonal unemployment?",
                'back': "Unemployment caused when an industry only operates during certain times of the year"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Real wage unemployment?",
                'back': "Unemployment caused when wages are set above the equilibrium wage rate"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Underemployment?",
                'back': "Those who are working part time, on zero hour contracts or on government training schemes but would prefer to be full time or those employed in areas below their skill level"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Labour Force Survey?",
                'back': "A measure of unemployment which surveys people to class them as unemployed, employed or inactive under the ILO definitions"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Claimant count?",
                'back': "A measure of unemployment; the number of people receiving benefits for being unemployed"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Aggregate demand (AD)?",
                'back': "The total level of demand in an economy at any given price level at any given moment in time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Aggregate supply (AS)?",
                'back': "The total amount of output in an economy at any given price at any given moment in time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Long run aggregate supply (LRAS)?",
                'back': "The total output an economy can produce when operating at full output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Short run aggregate supply (SRAS)?",
                'back': "Aggregate supply when at least one factor of production is fixed"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Animal spirits?",
                'back': "The level of confidence of business owners"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Consumption?",
                'back': "Consumer spending on goods and services"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Investment?",
                'back': "Spending by businesses on capital goods, which leads to the creation of real goods"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Government spending?",
                'back': "Spending by the government on the provision of goods and services"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Net exports?",
                'back': "Exports minus imports"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Fiscal policy?",
                'back': "The use of borrowing, government spending and taxation to manipulate the level of AD and improve macroeconomic performance"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Budget?",
                'back': "Where the government lays out their spending and taxation plans"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Budget deficit?",
                'back': "When the government spends more money than it receives"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Budget surplus?",
                'back': "When the government receives more money than it spends"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Direct tax?",
                'back': "Taxes paid straight to the government by the individual taxpayer"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Indirect tax?",
                'back': "Tax where the person charged with paying the money to the government is able to pass the cost onto someone else"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Expansionary policy?",
                'back': "Fiscal or monetary policy which is aimed at increasing AD"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Deflationary/contractionary policy?",
                'back': "Fiscal or monetary policy which is aimed at reducing AD"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monetary policy?",
                'back': "The attempts of the central bank/regulatory authority to control the level of AD by altering base interest rates or the amount of money in the economy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monetary Policy Committee (MPC)?",
                'back': "9 economists who meet monthly to set the Bank rate as well as other monetary instruments"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monetary supply?",
                'back': "Stock of money in the economy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Quantitative easing?",
                'back': "When the central bank buys assets in exchange for money in an attempt to increase the money supply"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Circular flow?",
                'back': "A model of the economy which shows the flow of goods and services, the factors of production and money around the economy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Injection?",
                'back': "Spending power entering the circular flow of income resulting from investment, government spending and exports"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Withdrawal?",
                'back': "Spending power leaving the circular flow of income resulting from savings, taxation and imports"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Multiplier?",
                'back': "An increase in an injection will lead to an even greater increase in national income"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal propensity to consume?",
                'back': "The proportion of an increase in income spent on consumption"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal propensity to save?",
                'back': "The proportion of an increase in income that is saved"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal propensity to tax?",
                'back': "The proportion of an increase in income that is taken away in tax"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal propensity to import?",
                'back': "The proportion of an increase in income spent on imports"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal propensity to withdraw?",
                'back': "The proportion of an increase in income that is withdrawn from the circular flow"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Balance of payments?",
                'back': "A record of all financial dealings over a period of time between economic agents of one country and all other countries"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Current account?",
                'back': "A record of the payments for the purchase and sale of goods and services as well as income and transfers"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Current account deficit?",
                'back': "When more money leaves the country than enters, so the current account is negative"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Current account surplus?",
                'back': "When more money enters the country than leaves, so the current account is positive"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Exports?",
                'back': "Goods and services sold to foreigners that bring income into the country"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Imports?",
                'back': "Goods and services bought from foreigners that takes income out of the country"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Export-led growth?",
                'back': "Economic growth arising from an increase in exports"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Purchasing power parity?",
                'back': "Exchange rate of one currency to another that compares the cost of living in different countries through comparing a typical basket of goods"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Trade (business) cycle?",
                'back': "The tendency of economic growth to rise and fall above and below the trend rate of economic growth, causing booms and busts"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Boom?",
                'back': "The peak of the business cycle, when growth is high"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Recession?",
                'back': "The trough of the business cycle, when growth is low. The government defines it as where real GDP falls in at least two successive quarters"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Supply-side policies?",
                'back': "Government policies aimed at increasing the productive potential of the economy and shifting LRAS to the right"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Market-based supply-side policies?",
                'back': "Policies which are designed to remove anything which prevents the free market system working efficiently"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Interventionist supply side policies?",
                'back': "Policies designed to correct market failure, where the government intervenes in the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Income?",
                'back': "A flow of assets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Wealth?",
                'back': "A stock of assets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Disposable income?",
                'back': "The money consumers have left to spend, after taxes have been taken away and benefits added"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Living standards?",
                'back': "The quality of life enjoyed by people in a country"
            }
        ],
        #Year 2 Microeconomics Flashcards
        'Microeconomics_2': [
            {
                'front': "What is Allocative efficiency?",
                'back': "When resources are allocated to the best interests of society, where there is maximum social welfare and maximum utility; P=MC"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Average cost/average total cost (AC/ATC)?",
                'back': "The cost of production per unit"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Average revenue?",
                'back': "The price each unit is sold for"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Bilateral monopoly?",
                'back': "Where there is only one buyer and one seller in the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Cartels?",
                'back': "A formal collusive agreement where firms enter into an agreement to mutually set prices"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Collusion?",
                'back': "Occurs when firms agree to work together, for example by setting a price or fixing the quantity they produce"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Competition policy?",
                'back': "Government action to increase competition in markets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Competitive tendering?",
                'back': "When the government contracts out the provision of a good or service and invites firms to bid for the contract"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Conglomerate integration?",
                'back': "The merger of firms with no common connection"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Constant returns to scale?",
                'back': "Output increases by the same proportion that the inputs increase by"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Contestable market?",
                'back': "When there is the threat of new entrants into the market, forcing firms to be efficient"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Decreasing returns to scale?",
                'back': "An increase in inputs by a certain proportion will lead to output increasing by a smaller proportion"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Demergers?",
                'back': "A single business is broken into two or more businesses to operate on their own, to be sold or to be dissolved"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Deregulation?",
                'back': "The removal of legal barriers to allow private enterprises to compete in a previously protected market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Derived demand?",
                'back': "The demand for one good is linked to the demand for a related good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Diminishing marginal productivity?",
                'back': "If a variable factor is increased when another factor is fixed, there will come a point when each extra unit of the variable factor will produce less extra output than the previous unit; after a certain point, marginal output falls"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Diseconomies of scale?",
                'back': "The disadvantages that arise in large businesses that reduce efficiency and cause average costs to rise"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Divorce of ownership from control?",
                'back': "Firms are owned by shareholders, who have little say in the day to day running of the business, and controlled by managers; this leads to the principal-agent problem"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Dynamic efficiency?",
                'back': "Efficiency in the long run; concerned with new technology and increases in productivity which causes efficiency to increase over a period of time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Economies of scale?",
                'back': "The advantages of large scale production that enable a large business to produce at a lower average cost than a smaller business"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are External economies of scale?",
                'back': "An advantage which arises from the growth of the industry within which the firm operates, independent of the firm itself"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Fixed cost?",
                'back': "Costs which do not vary with output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are For profit businesses?",
                'back': "A business whose main aim is to make money"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Game theory?",
                'back': "Used to predict the outcome of a decision made by one firm, which has incomplete information about the other firm"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Geographical mobility of labour?",
                'back': "The ease and speed at which labour can move from one area to another"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Horizontal integration?",
                'back': "The merger of firms in the same industry at the same stage of production"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Increasing returns to scale?",
                'back': "An increase in inputs by a certain proportion will lead to an increase in output by a larger proportion"
            },
            {
                'front': "What does Interdependent mean?",
                'back': "The actions of one firm directly affects another firm"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Internal economies of scale?",
                'back': "An advantage that a firm is able to enjoy because of growth in the firm, independent of anything happening to other firms or the industry in general"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Limit pricing?",
                'back': "When firms set prices low in order to prevent new entrants; used in contestable markets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Loss?",
                'back': "When revenue does not cover costs"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal cost?",
                'back': "The additional cost of producing one extra unit of good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marginal revenue?",
                'back': "The additional revenue gained by selling one extra unit of good"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Maximum wage?",
                'back': "A ceiling wage which people cannot earn above"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Minimum efficient scale?",
                'back': "The lowest level of output necessary to fully exploit economies of scale"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Minimum wage?",
                'back': "A floor wage which people cannot earn below"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monopolistic competition?",
                'back': "Where there are a large number of buyers and sellers who are relatively small and act independently, selling non-homogenous goods"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monopoly?",
                'back': "A single seller in the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Monopsony?",
                'back': "A single buyer in the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is N-firm concentration ratio?",
                'back': "The percentage of market share held by the 'n' biggest firms"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Nationalisation?",
                'back': "When a private sector company or industry is brought under state control, to be owned and managed by the government"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Natural monopoly?",
                'back': "Where economies of scale are so large that not even a single producer is able to fully exploit them; it is more efficient for there to be a monopoly than many sellers"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Non-collusive oligopoly?",
                'back': "When firms in an oligopoly compete against each other, rather than making agreements to reduce competition"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Non-price competition?",
                'back': "When firms compete on factors other than price, for example customer service or quality; they aim to increase the loyalty to the brand which makes demand more inelastic"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Normal profit?",
                'back': "The minimum reward required to keep entrepreneurs supplying their enterprise, the return sufficient to keep the factors of production committed to the business; TC=TR"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Not-for-profit business?",
                'back': "Where firms are run in order to maximise social welfare and help individuals and groups; any profit they do make is used to support their aims"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Occupational mobility of labour?",
                'back': "The ease and speed at which labour can move from one type of job to another"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Oligopoly?",
                'back': "Where a few firms dominate the market and have the majority of market share, they act interdependently"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Organic growth?",
                'back': "When firms grow by increasing their output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Overt collusion?",
                'back': "Collusion where firms come to a formal agreement, for example a cartel"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Perfect competition?",
                'back': "A market with many buyers and sellers selling homogenous goods with perfect information and freedom of entry and exit"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Perfectly contestable market?",
                'back': "A market with no barriers to entry, where a new firm can easily enter and compete against incumbent firms completely equally"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Predatory pricing?",
                'back': "When a large, established firm is threatened by new entrants so sets such a low price that other firms make losses and are driven out the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Price leadership?",
                'back': "Where one firm sets prices and other firms tend to follow this firm as they are fearful of engaging in a price war"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Price wars?",
                'back': "When firms continuously drive prices down to the point where they are frequently making losses and firms are forced to leave"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Principal-agent problem?",
                'back': "Where the agent makes decisions on behalf of the principal; the agent should maximise the benefits of the principal but have the temptation of maximising their own benefits"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Private sector?",
                'back': "The part of the economy that is owned and run by individuals or groups of individuals"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Privatisation?",
                'back': "The sale of government equity in nationalised industries or other firms to private investors"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Productive efficiency?",
                'back': "When resources are used to give the maximum possible output at the lowest possible cost; MC=AC"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Profit maximisation?",
                'back': "When firms produce at a point which derives the greatest profit; MC=MR"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Profit satisficing?",
                'back': "When a firm earn just enough profit to keep its shareholders happy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Public sector?",
                'back': "The part of the economy that is owned and controlled by local or central government"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Regulatory capture?",
                'back': "When regulators become more empathetic and are able to 'see things from the firm's perspective', which removes impartiality and weakens their ability to regulate"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Revenue maximisation?",
                'back': "When firms produce at a point which derives the greatest revenue; MR=0"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Sales maximisation?",
                'back': "When firms produce at a point where they sell as many of their goods and services as possible without making a loss; AR=AC"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Static efficiency?",
                'back': "The level of efficiency at one point in time"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Sunk costs?",
                'back': "Costs that can't be recovered once they have been spent"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Supernormal profit?",
                'back': "The profit above normal profit, TR>TC"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Tacit collusion?",
                'back': "Collusion where there is no formal agreement, such as price leadership"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Third degree price discrimination?",
                'back': "When monopolists charge different prices to different groups for the same good or service"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Total cost (TC)?",
                'back': "The cost to produce a given level of output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Total revenue (TR)?",
                'back': "Revenue generated from the sale of a given level of output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Variable costs?",
                'back': "Costs which change with output"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Vertical integration?",
                'back': "When a firm merges or takes over another firm in the same industry, but at a different stage of production"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is X-inefficiency?",
                'back': "When firms produce at a cost above the AC curve"
            }
        ],
        #Year 2 Macroeconomics Flashcards
        'Macroeconomics_2': [
            {
                'front': "What is Absolute advantage?",
                'back': "When a country can produce a good more cheaply in absolute terms than another country"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Absolute poverty?",
                'back': "When people are unable to afford sufficient necessities to maintain life; those on less than $1.90 a day"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Aid?",
                'back': "When a country voluntarily transfers resources to another or gives loans on a concessionary basis"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Appreciation?",
                'back': "An increase in the value of the currency using floating exchange rates"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Automatic stabilisers?",
                'back': "Mechanisms which reduce the impact of changes in the economy on national income"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Balance of payments?",
                'back': "A record of all financial dealings over a period of time between economic agents of one country and another"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Buffer stock systems?",
                'back': "When a maximum and minimum price are imposed together in order to bring about price stability"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Capital account?",
                'back': "A part of the balance of payments; records debt forgiveness, inheritance taxes, transfers of financial assets and sales of assets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Capital expenditure?",
                'back': "Government spending on investment goods such as new roads, schools and hospitals, which will be consumed in over a year"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Capital flight?",
                'back': "When large amounts of money are taken out of the country, rather than being left there for people to borrow and invest"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Central banks?",
                'back': "A financial institution that has direct responsibility to control the money supply and monetary policy, to manage gold reserves and foreign currency and to issue government debt"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Common market?",
                'back': "Members trade freely in all economic resources and impose a common external tariff"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Comparative advantage?",
                'back': "When a country is able to produce a good more cheaply relative to other goods produced; it has a lower opportunity cost"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Current account?",
                'back': "A part of the balance of payments; records payments for the purchase and sale of goods and services, as well as incomes and transfers"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Customs union?",
                'back': "The removal of all tariff barriers between members and the introduction of a common external tariff"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Current expenditure?",
                'back': "General government final consumption plus transfer payments plus interest payments"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Cyclical deficit?",
                'back': "The part of the deficit that occurs because government spending fluctuates around the trade cycle"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Depreciation?",
                'back': "A fall in the value of the currency using floating exchange rates"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Devaluation?",
                'back': "When the currency is decreased against another under a fixed system"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Developed country?",
                'back': "Countries with high GDP per capita and a high standard of living"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is a Developing country?",
                'back': "Countries with a low GDP per capita and a low standard of living"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Discretionary fiscal policy?",
                'back': "Deliberate manipulation of government expenditure and taxes to influence the economy; expansionary and deflationary fiscal policy"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Economic development?",
                'back': "Improvements in living standards"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Emerging economies?",
                'back': "A country that is growing quickly and has some characteristics of a developed country but is not fully there yet"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Exchange rate?",
                'back': "The purchasing power of a currency in terms of what it can buy of other currencies"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Financial account?",
                'back': "A part of the balance of payments; records FDI, portfolio investment and the transfer of gold and currency reserves"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Financial markets?",
                'back': "When buyers and sellers can buy and trade a range of services or assets that are fundamentally monetary in nature"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Fiscal deficit?",
                'back': "When the government spends more than it receives each year"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Fixed exchange rate?",
                'back': "The value of the currency is set against the value of another and that exchange rate does not change"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Foreign currency gap?",
                'back': "When a country does not export enough to finance the purchase of goods from overseas"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Foreign direct investment?",
                'back': "Investment by one private sector company in one country into another private sector company in another"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Free trade?",
                'back': "Trade with no barriers or restrictions"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Free trade agreements?",
                'back': "When two or more countries in a region agree to reduce/eliminate trade barriers on all goods from member countries"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Free floating exchange rate?",
                'back': "Value of the currency is determined purely by market demand and supply of the currency"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is General government final consumption?",
                'back': "Spending on goods and services which will be consumed within the next year"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Gini coefficient?",
                'back': "A measure of income inequality; the ratio of the area between the 45 degree line and the Lorenz curve and the whole area under the 45 degree line"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Globalisation?",
                'back': "The growing interdependence of countries and the rapid rate of change it brings about; movement towards free trade of goods and services, free movement of labour and capital and free interchange of technology and intellectual capital"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Harrod-Domar model?",
                'back': "Savings provide the funds that are used for investment, and growth rates depend on the level of savings and the productivity of investment. Therefore, growth in developing countries is limited by the lack of investment"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Human Development Index (HDI)?",
                'back': "Measures an economy's development based on income, health and education"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Infrastructure?",
                'back': "Facilities required for an economy to function, such as roads"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is International competitiveness?",
                'back': "The ability of a country to compete effectively and become attractive in international markets"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is J-Curve?",
                'back': "The current account will worsen before it improves following a depreciation of the currency"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Laffer curve?",
                'back': "Shows that a rise in tax rates does not necessarily lead to a rise in tax revenues, due to the impact on incentives and work"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Lewis 2 model?",
                'back': "A model which suggests that countries will develop through industrialisation as labour is moved from the unproductive agriculture sector to the more productive urban sector. This increases wages and leads to move saving and investment."
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Lorenz curve?",
                'back': "The cumulative percentage of population plotted against the cumulative percentage of income that those people have"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Market bubbles?",
                'back': "When the price of an asset rises massively and greatly exceeds the value of the asset itself"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Market rigging?",
                'back': "A group of individuals or institutions collude to fix prices or exchange information that will lead to gains for themselves at the expense of other participants in the market"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Microfinance schemes?",
                'back': "Schemes which aim to give poor and near-poor households permanent access to a range of financial services"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Managed floating exchange rate?",
                'back': "Value of the currency is determined by demand and supply but the Central Bank intervenes to prevent large changes"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Marshall-Lerner condition?",
                'back': "The sum of the price elasticities of imports and exports must be more than one if a currency depreciation is to have a positive impact on the trade balance"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Monetary unions?",
                'back': "Two or more countries with a single currency"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Moral hazard?",
                'back': "When individuals act in their own best interests knowing there are potential risks- another cause of financial market failure"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is National debt?",
                'back': "The sum of government debts built up over many years"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Primary product dependency?",
                'back': "When a country relies heavily on primary products, such as agricultural goods or mining"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Progressive taxation?",
                'back': "Where those on higher incomes pay a higher marginal rate of tax; those on higher incomes pay a higher percentage of their income on tax"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Proportional taxation?",
                'back': "The proportion of income paid on the tax remains the same whilst the income of the taxpayer changes; everyone pays the same percentage of their income on tax"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Protectionism?",
                'back': "When governments enact policies to restrict the free entry of imports into their country, such as tariffs and quotas"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Quotas?",
                'back': "Limits placed on the level of imports allowed into a country"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Regressive taxation?",
                'back': "Where the proportion of income paid in tax falls whilst the income of the taxpayer increases; those on lower incomes pay a higher percentage of their income on tax"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Relative poverty?",
                'back': "When income falls below an average income threshold. In the UK, this is those on less than 60% of the median household income"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Revaluation?",
                'back': "When the currency is increased against the value of another under a fixed system"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Speculation?",
                'back': "Trading financial assets in hope of significant returns"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Structural deficit?",
                'back': "The deficit which occurs when the cyclical deficit is 0"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Tariffs?",
                'back': "Taxes placed on imported goods in an attempt to prevent people from buying them"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Terms of trade?",
                'back': "The ratio of an index of a country's exports to an index of its import prices"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Theory of comparative advantage?",
                'back': "Countries will find specialisation mutually advantageous if the opportunity costs of production are different"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Trade creation?",
                'back': "When a country moves from buying goods from a high cost to a lower cost producer"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Trade diversion?",
                'back': "When a country moves from buying goods from a low cost producer to a higher cost one"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Trade liberalisation?",
                'back': "Reduction or removal of protectionist policies"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Trading bloc?",
                'back': "A group of countries that reduce or remove trade barriers between them"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Transfer payments?",
                'back': "Government spending for which there is no corresponding output, where money is taken from one group and given to another"
            },
            {
                'front': "What is Transfer pricing?",
                'back': "Where firms manipulate the price of their good so that profit is increased in areas of low tax"
            },
            {
                'front': "What are Unit labour costs?",
                'back': "The cost of employing workers for each unit of a good"
            }
        ],
        # Maths Placeholder Flashcards
        'Pure_Mathematics_1': [
            {
                'front': "This is a placeholder question for Pure Mathematics Year 1. Content to be added",
                'back': "This is a placeholder answer for Pure Mathematics Year 1. Content to be added."
            }
        ],
        
        # Computer Science Placeholder Flashcards
        'Computer_Systems_1': [
            {
                'front': "This is a placeholder question for Computer Systems Year 1. Content to be added",
                'back': "This is a placeholder answer for Computer Systems Year 1. Content to be added."
            }
        ],
    }
    return flashcards_by_year